

PROFILE

Proficient Senior Digital Marketing Analyst with 12+ years of experience. Strategic and innovative with a passion for Driving Brand Awareness and Product Performance. Eager to fulfil a Marketing Expert/Manager to positively contribute to your reputed organization.

CONTACT

PHONE: +91-99812 86565

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ansv67

EMAIL: verma_anshul28@hotmail.com

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Analytics Individual Certification
March 2021 – March 2022

Google Search Advertising Certification
March 2021 – March 2022

TOOLS

- Google Search Console
- Google Analytics & Tag Manager
- Google Data Studio
- SEMRUSH, XENU, AHREF, Woorank, UberSuggest
- KEYWORD SPY, SPYFU, ALEXA, KeywordTool.io
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- WordPress, Magento, Joomla, Shopify, Drupal, Zen Cart, Open Cart, Squarespace, Prestashop, Wix
- Hootsuite, BUZZSUMO
- FileZilla
- Callrail & Whatconverts
- MS Office, Libre Office, Google Docs
- MailChimp, Get Response, SendGrid, Klaviyo

EXPERTISE

- Search Engine Marketing (SEM)
- Email Marketing
- Digital Marketing
- Reputation Management
- Content Management & Marketing
- Social Media Marketing (SMM)
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

SKILLS

- Excellent Communication Skills
- Strategic Planning
- Project & Team Management
- Case Studies & Estimation Preparation
- Schema Tag Implementation/ Google Penalty Removal

ANSHUL VERMA

SENIOR DIGITAL MARKETING ANALYST

EDUCATION

Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidhalya

July 2004 - June 2008

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

Codiant [Yash Technologies Company] - Senior Digital Marketing Analyst Sep 2021 – To present

- Project Management, Direct Communication and Reporting.
- Prepared Proposal, Estimation & Case studies to increase Clientele.

Rave Digital - Senior Digital Marketing Analyst

May 2020 - Aug 2021

- Generated \$ 3 Million in revenue with 900% ROAS from Google Ads for Healthcare Website.
- Handle Shopping Ads, Search Ads, Display Ads, Facebook Ads & Pinterest Ads for eCommerce business and product websites.
- Developed Use-Case Automation Flow and Newsletter Workflows for Magento B2B (Subsidiary: Aheadworks.com - Premium Magento Extension Builder)
- Monitor KPI movements from all digital marketing assets, trends, anomalies, and opportunities using Online Marketing Report.
- Collaborated with Graphic Designer Team and Creative Writers for effective Digital Storytelling to generate quality leads.
- Well versed with the latest Google trends.

The House of Ankit – Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Manger

February 2020 – May 2020

• Increased Sales by 15% through Organic via Store Optimization & promotions.

Cyber Infrastructure (CIS) – Associate Team Lead

March 2013 - February 2020

- Managed SEM, SEO, SMO, Email Marketing and Reputation Management for various Industry sectors.
- Implemented Advanced Google Analytics including Enhanced E-commerce, Event Tracking, Goal Setup, and Custom Reporting to track websites and mobile apps.

Rack Bank – Senior Search Engine Optimization (SEO) - Search Engine Marketing (SEM) Expert

February 2012 – March 2013

- Developed, implement and managed several Marketing Campaigns for various clients
- Developed websites for several clients.

Syscraft – Senior Search Engine Optimization (SEO) - Search Engine Marketing (SEM) Expert

May 2011 - January 2012

 SEO role with emphasis on Implementation of various On-page, Off-page and Reputation management tactics.

InfoBeans – Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Consultant

September 2010 – January 2011

 Researched and implemented Off-page SEO tactics like Directory Submission, Article Submission, Press Release Submission, Forum Posting, Classified Ads, Social Bookmarking.

SNV Infotech – Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Team Leader

July 2009 – August 2010

- Learnt the basic principles & SEO guidelines to deliver quality results to clients.
- Promoted quickly to the position of a Team leader.